如果你想买票
If you want any tickets,
你应该走前面…
you'll have to go around to the front of...
哦，我想这样也可以
Well, I suppose it'll be all right.
我是在这儿干什么呀？
What the hell am I doing around here?
他们走进来还要…
They walk in here and...
让我看看，我希望我有…
Let's see. I hope I got...
三张？
Three?
七美元…
That'll be $7...
…五十分
...and 50 cents.
不
No.
弗兰克？
Frank?
弗兰克叫我们来
Frank sent us.
你们给我带马来了吗？
Did you bring a horse for me?
好啊，看起来我们…
Well, looks like we're...
看起来我们不好意思只带一匹来
Looks like we're shy one horse.
你带两匹来太多了
You brought two too many.
嗨，爸！
Hey, Pa!
看！
Look!
够了，时候不早了，回家去
That's enough for now. It's getting late. Come on home.
提米
Timmy.
穆琳，看哪
Maureen, look.
你在这里干嘛？进屋去，快，去洗一下
What you doing there? Go inside, quick, and get washed.
不要碰苹果派和烤肉
And don't touch the apple pie or the roast.
帕特里克已经出发去火车站了？
Patrick's already left for the station, huh?
他刚刚准备好，爸
He's getting ready, Pa.
- 快点，帕特里克！ - 来了，爸
- Damn it, Patrick!      - Coming, Pa.
不得不说，还不错
Not bad, I'd say.
大些，那些片，怎么回事？我们是在准备宴会，不是吗？
Bigger, them slices. What the hell? We're throwing a party, ain't we?
但是这些和以前的一样
But these are the same slices as usual.
是的，当然
Yeah, sure.
和以前一样
As usual.
穆琳
Maureen.
过不了不久，如果你愿意你可以把面包切的和门一样大
Soon, you can cut the bread in slices as big as a door if you want to.
你会有漂亮的新衣服
You'll have beautiful new clothes
再也不用干活了
and you won't have to work no more.
我们要变富了吗，爸？
We're going to get rich, Pa?
天知道？
Who knows?
帕特里克！
Patrick!
等一等！
Wait a minute!
看看你靴子上的脏东西 去弄干净
Look at the filth on your boots. Clean them.
火车就要到了
The train will come in
不想没有人接你妈吧
and there won't be no one to meet your mother.
我妈六年前就死了
Our mother died six years ago.
快走，否则你真的要迟了
Go now, or you'll really be late.
嗨，等一下，爸 我怎么认出来她？
Just a minute. Listen, Pa. How am I gonna recognize her?
你绝不会认错的，帕特里克
You can't make no mistake, Patrick.
她年轻 她漂亮 她是位女士
She's young and she's pretty and she's a lady.
“旅行中，我会穿一件黑衣服
"For traveling, I'll be wearing a black dress
头戴认识你时的那顶帽子”
"and the same straw hat that I was wearing when we met."
我去井里打点水来
I'm gonna get some fresh water from the well.
噢，丹尼男孩[爱尔兰民歌：丹尼男孩]
Oh, Danny boy
笛声正在呼唤
The pipes, the pipes are calling
越过峡谷下到山腰
And down the mountain side
夏日已经过去
The summer's gone
花儿都已凋谢…
And all the roses fall...
穆琳！
Maureen!
这一个怎么办，弗兰克？
What are we gonna do with this one, Frank?
你都已经叫出我的名字了…
Now that you've called me by name...
在南面我看到一些优质原料
I saw some mighty fine stock down south.
是吗？
Is that so?
价格也很公道
And the prices are good.
- 这些是你的行李吗，女士？ - 是的
- These your valises, ma'am?      - Yes.
- 过来，山姆 - 拿另外两个
- Come, Sarah. - Bring them other two.
我们帮你背，女士
We'll tote them for you, ma'am.
真的吗？锯木厂真的需要帮手？
Is that true? The sawmill needs hands?
- 昨天还找人去 - 为什么不告诉你兄弟？
- Was yesterday. - Why didn't you tell your brother?
- 嗨，老爷子 - 嗨，比尔，我们又回来了
- Hiya, Gramps. - Hiya, Bill. We're back again.
来吧，还不快点，你？
Come on. Get a move on, will you?
快去找你们的头儿，你们这些红皮肤的战士们
Get the lead out of your asses, you redskin warriors.
我还有一整车的货要卸
I got a whole train to unload.
好了，先把那些饲料袋扔下来
All right, chuck down those feed sacks first.
快点！快点！
Come on! Come on!
你要去什么地方？
What's the name of the place you wanted to go?
甜水镇
Sweetwater.
布赖特·马克贝恩的农场
Brett McBain's farm.
马克贝恩？噢，是吗
McBain? Yeah, sure.
那个顽固的红头发爱尔兰人
That stubborn redheaded Irishman,
在荒无人烟的沙漠中央耕种沙子
tilling sand for years way out there in the middle of nowhere.
甜水！
Sweetwater!
只有他那样的疯子
Only a loony like him could call
才把那块地上不长毛的沙漠叫作甜水
that stinking piece of desert Sweetwater.
甜水！
Sweetwater!
嗨呀！甜水！
That's good! Sweetwater!
往右边来一点 高一点
That's right. A little more to the right.
高一点
Higher. Higher.
那儿正好
Hold it there.
那儿正好 这些家伙把铁路铺到这里来了
Here they are. Even got here with their damn rails.
他们又赶上我们了，拉斐德？我们走！
They caught up with us again, eh, Lafayette? Let's go!
慢一点 你怎么搞的？慢一点！
Hey, slow down. What's the matter with you? Slow down!
那边的！让一让！
Hey, boys! Watch out!
那边的让一让！
Watch out down there!
慢一点！
Slow down!
为什么停下？我说过我很着急
Why are we stopping? I told you I was in a hurry.
火车不是也要停吗？
Don't the train stop?
能为您做点什么，女士？
What can I do for you, ma'am?
我想要点水，如果不介意的话
I would like some water, if it's no trouble.
水？
Water?
在这里那个词好比毒药
Well, you see, that word is poison around these parts
自从那场大洪水后
ever since the days of the great flood.
- 你是说你们从来不洗澡？ - 当然我们洗！
- You mean you never wash?       - We sure do!
我愿意用你们用的相同的东西
I'd like to use the same facilities you people do.
当然你可以
You sure can.
后面正好有一个装满的浴缸
Just happen to have a full tub in the back.
你很幸运
And you're lucky.
今天早上才有三个人用过
Only three people have used it this morning.
一个一个用的还是一起？
Used it one at a time or all together?
我敢说你过惯了舒适的生活
I can tell you're accustomed to fine living.
你一定是从东部某个大城市来的吧
Bet you come from one of those big eastern cities.
- 新奥尔良 - 新奥尔良！
- New Orleans. - New Orleans!
- 你去过？   - 没
- You've been there? - No.
但是我有个表姐在那儿 她开了个酒吧
But I got a cousin down there. She runs a bar.
知道么，她…
You know, she...
一整瓶
Jug.
你只知道怎么演奏还是知道怎么开枪？
Do you only know how to play or do you know how to shoot?
知道怎么用那个吹曲子吗？
Do you know how to blow music from that?
捡起来
Pick it up.
你！
You!
你不会玩
You don't know how to play.
试试这个
Try this one.
拿着
Take it.
快点
Go on.
这儿
Here.
做得好
Bravo.
夏恩
Cheyenne.
还以为我们赶不及呢
We thought we'd never make it.
还行 你们很准时
It's all right. You're right on time.
把那个护卫埋了
To bury my escort.
如果等你，我现在已经在监狱里了
If I'd waited for you, I'd be in jail by now.
我的枪
The gun.
你很赶时髦，口琴家？
You interested in fashions, Harmonica?
不久之前我看到三件这样的外套
I saw three of these dusters a short time ago.
在等一列火车
They were waiting for a train.
三个穿这种外套的家伙
Inside the dusters, there were three men.
然后呢？
So?
每个人身体里都有一颗子弹
Inside the men, there were three bullets.
骗人的故事，口琴家
That's a crazy story, Harmonica.
两个原因
For two reasons.
第一个，这里没有人
One, nobody around these parts got the guts
敢穿这种外套除了夏恩的人
to wear those dusters except Cheyenne's men.
第二个，夏恩的人不会被杀
Two, Cheyenne's men don't get killed.
你吃惊了吗？
That surprise you?
是的
Yeah.
哦，你懂音乐
Well, you know music.
还能把所有的东西 数到二
And you can count. All the way up to two.
数到六，如果我必须
All the way up to six, if I have to.
也许要比你快
And maybe faster than you.
好，继续
Yeah, go on.
吹吧，口琴家
Play, Harmonica.
吹吧，就不会胡言乱语了
Play, so you can't bullshit.
但是，小心那些错误的注解
Only, watch those false notes.
比如？
Like so?
我的这个表姐
And so, this cousin of mine
总是写信邀请我去新奥尔良
keeps writing me to come on down to New Orleans.
“过来吧，帮我照料酒吧，多挣点钱”
"Come on down. Help me with the bar. Make a pile of money."
我想我适应不了大城市的生活
I don't think I'd get along in a big city.
到处是放荡的男人和女人
It's too full of fast men and loose women.
对不起，女士 不
Begging your pardon, ma'am. No.
现在我习惯了安静简单的乡下生活
Now, I'm too used to a quiet, simple country life.
他是提米
He's Timmy.
是的
Yes.
天哪
Dear God.
那天…
On the day...
在你婚礼的那天
On the very day of your wedding.
可怜的小姐
Poor little miss.
夫人
Mrs...
马克贝恩夫人
Mrs. McBain.
但是我们都… 我们以为…
But we all... But we thought...
我知道
I know.
今天你们一定很吃惊
It was to be a surprise today.
布赖特·马克贝恩和我结了婚
Brett McBain and I were married.
一个月之前
A month ago.
在新奥尔良
In New Orleans.
“复活在我 生命也在我”
"I am the resurrection, and the life.
“信我的人，虽然死了，也必复活”
"He that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live.
“凡活着信我的人必永远不死”
"Whosoever liveth and believeth in me shall never die."
阿门
Amen.
- 贝奈特先生！ - 他在这里做什么？
- Mr. Bennett!      - What's he doing here?
我发现这个衣领，钉在门上
I found this collar on a nail by the door.
你没办法知道，但这是个最好的签名
You got no way of knowing, but this is as good as a signature.
夏恩的手下
Cheyenne's hand.
- 但是为什么？ - 别着急，马克贝恩女士
- But why?          - Don't worry, Mrs. McBain.
在绞死他们之前，我们会让他们说的
We'll make them tell us before we hang them.
我们走吧
Let's get moving.
走吧
Come on.
我们回石板镇吧
Let's go back to Flagstone.
不，山姆
No, Sam.
你回去吧
You go back.
你不会想一个人留在这里吧？
You don't want to stay out here alone.
为什么不呢？
Why not?
这是我的家
This is my home.
知道吗，无赖
You know, Wobbles,
你让我发火了
I'm kind of mad at you.
弗兰克不在那儿
Frank wasn't there.
他叫了三个朋友去
He sent three friends.
我什么都不知道，我发誓
I don't know nothing, I swear.
我只是按你的意思安排了那个会面
I only arranged the meeting the way you wanted it.
我不知道为什么弗兰克没去
I don't know why Frank wasn't there.
- 我对你发誓我… - 因为他在马克贝恩家
- I swear to you that I... - 'Cause he was at the McBains'.
不是他 那是夏恩做的
That's not true. Cheyenne did that job.
每个人都知道 我们有证据
Everyone knows that. We got proof.
那不过是弗兰克玩的把戏
That was always one of Frank's tricks.
捏造证据
Faking evidence.
我不知道
I don't know.
我发誓
I swear.
我只是安排了会面，我发誓
I only arranged the meeting. I swear.
我什么都不知道
I don't know nothing.
谁在那儿？
Who's there?
你会做咖啡吗？
Did you make coffee?
去做
Make it.
一晚上没合眼
Didn't sleep a wink.
一群穿黑衣服的卑鄙小人追了我整整一夜
A pack of turds dressed in black rode herd on me the whole damn night.
是的，不过我把他们甩到沙漠里了
Yeah, but I left them in the middle of the desert.
幸运的话，他们三天后会回来
If they're lucky, they'll be home in three days.
我做这个 你去拿咖啡
I'll do it. You fetch the coffee.
他们想绞死我 那些黑乌鸦
They want to hang me, the big black crows.
白痴
Idiots.
为什么？
What the hell?
我会杀任何人 但是决不包括孩子
I'll kill anything, but never a kid.
可以去杀神父
Be like killing a priest.
一个天主教的神父，仅此而已
A Catholic priest, that is.
是啊，这个世界上有很多人痛恨夏恩
Yeah, the world is full of people who hate Cheyenne.
看，我并不是人们所说的那种混蛋
See, I ain't the mean bastard people make out.
当然，如果有人想杀我
Of course, if somebody had a mind to kill me,
激怒我
it fires me up.
被激怒了的夏恩
And a fired-up Cheyenne
可不是好惹的
ain't a nice thing to see.
特别是对于一个女士
Especially for a lady.
但是你很聪明不会去激怒他
But you're too smart to make him mad.
这就是那个说我杀了所有人的地方吗？
So this here's where I was supposed to do all the killing?
哼
Yeah.
没看出来哪里值得
Don't seem the place is worth a shit.
那么，如果有人打扮得像我一样
Now, if somebody gets dressed up to look like me,
他们就可以把这事扯在我头上
so they can hang this thing around my neck,
我一点也不喜欢这样
I don't like it none.
但是可以理解
But I can understand it.
我不明白的是为了什么
What I don't understand is why.
我也不明白
Neither do I.
但是我觉得你知道的很多
But I see you looked a lot for the why.
没错
Yeah.
如果有一整堆问题呢？
What if there were a whole heap of whys?
圆的，黄的（形容各种豆子）
Round. Yellow.
你知道的
You know the kind.
你把他们扔到石头上
You rap them on a stone
他们噼啪作响
and they go "ding."
也许
Maybe.
但是我还没有找到他们
But I didn't find them.
顺便问一下
By the way,
你知不知道一个到处吹口琴的家伙？
you know anything about a man going around playing a harmonica?
你应该记住他
He's somebody you'd remember.
他不说话而吹口琴
Instead of talking, he plays.
当他应该吹的时候，他却说话
And when he'd better play, he talks.
你明白，如果你已经杀了四个，很容易再有第五个
You know, ma'am, when you've Killed four, it's easy to make it five.
确实如此 你是个行家
Sure. You're an expert.
夫人，看起来你没有理解我的意思
Ma'am, it seems to me you ain't caught the idea.
我当然明白
Of course I have.
我孤零零一个人落在一伙见钱眼开的强盗手里
I'm here alone in the hands of a bandit who smelled money.
如果你愿意，你可以凌辱我寻开心
If you want to, you can lay me over the table and amuse yourself.
甚至叫你的人进来
And even call in your men.
没有女人因为那样而死
Well, no woman ever died from that.
你完事后，我需要的仅仅是一盆开水
When you're finished, all I'll need will be a tub of boiling water,
然后我会和以前完全一样
and I'll be exactly what I was before.
不过是又多了一个肮脏的回忆而已
With just another filthy memory.
你的咖啡还不错
You make good coffee, at least?
不错
Not bad.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
告诉我，有没有必要把他们全部杀掉？
Tell me, was it necessary that you kill all of them?
我只是告诉你吓吓他们
I only told you to scare them.
当他们死亡的时候是最恐惧的时候
People scare better when they're dying.
你能说说你的屠杀有什么好处吗？
And can you tell me what good was your stupid massacre?
现在，出来了一个马克贝恩夫人
Now, a Mrs. McBain has turned up.
我没有料到那个 是个意外
So, I didn't expect that. It happens in business.
这么说吧 这是我们没有计划到的
Let's say this is something I didn't plan on.
我没有时间去吃惊了，弗兰克
I have no time for surprises, Frank.
你知道
You know that.
我要上船去看一看大西洋
I got on board in sight of the Atlantic,
在我的眼睛瞎掉之前
and before my eyes rot,
我想看看窗外蓝色的大西洋
I want to see the blue of the Pacific outside that window.
我知道你在哪里上火车的
I know where you got on board.
别忘了，我也在那里
I was there, too, remember?
“清除掉道路上的障碍” 你说过
"To remove small obstacles from the track," you said.
哦，还有一些
Well, there were a few.
但是我们走了很远，还是一样
But we traveled a long way, just the same.
而且很快
And fast.
骨头上的结核也走得很快
Even tuberculosis of the bones travels fast.
别把我当病人，莫顿先生
Don't play the sick man with me, Mr. Morton.
你刚刚开始腿瘸我就认识你了
I knew you when you were just barely limping.
我看着你那枯掉的肢体一天天吞噬你
I watch that dry rot rise a little more every day.
任何一个正常人都会给自己来颗子弹的
Any normal man would put a bullet in his brain.
然而你，只是变得稍微有些急躁
But you, you just got a little more hasty.
别的你一点都没变
Otherwise you ain't changed any.
你变了，弗兰克
I'd say you've changed, Frank.
很多
A lot.
你过去总是亲自去做事情
You used to take care of certain things personally.
现在 你要隐藏在幕后
Now, you're keeping in the background.
你会最终发号施令
You'll end up giving orders.
因为，目前，我不想让你总是一个人
It's because, now, I don't want to leave you alone too much.
你需要越来越多的人和你在一起
You're gonna need somebody more and more every day to stay near you.
- 朋友       - 或是同伙
- Like a friend. - Or like a partner.
坐在那个桌子后面感觉如何，弗兰克？
How does it feel sitting behind that desk, Frank?
就像握着一把枪
It's almost like holding a gun.
不过更有威力些
Only much more powerful.
你看 和你在一起
You see, staying with you,
我也变得目光远大了
I'm beginning to think big, too.
这次马克贝恩事件
This McBain business
给了我一个想法
has given me ideas.
我很抱歉，弗兰克，你做的很好
I'm sorry for you, Frank. You're doing your best.
但是你永远无法取得像我一样的成功
You'll never succeed in becoming like me.
为什么？
Why?
因为有很多事情你永远都不会不明白
Because there are many things you'll never understand.
这就是其中之一
This is one of them.
看，弗兰克，有很多种武器
You see, Frank, there are many kinds of weapons.
唯一能平息这场风波的是它
And the only one that can stop that is this.
现在应该回到我们的小麻烦上了吧？
Now, shall we get back to our little problem?
也许你认为我的武器很简单，莫顿先生
My weapons might look simple to you, Mr. Morton,
但它仍旧可以在我们的小麻烦上打个窟窿
but they can still shoot holes big enough for our little problems.
过不了多久，那个马克贝恩寡妇就不会再是个麻烦了
Pretty soon the widow McBain won't be a problem no more.
清晨，你醒来说“世界，我了解你”
You wake up one morning and say, "World, I know you.
“从现在开始，不再有惊奇”
"From now on, there are no more surprises."
然后你偶尔碰倒了一个这样的男人
And then you happen to meet a man like this,
看起来像是一个好男人
who looked like a good man.
清澈的目光，强壮的臂膀
Clear eyes, strong hands.
他想娶你
And he wants to marry you.
这种事不常发生
Which doesn't happen often.
他说他还很富有，那并不重要
And he says he's rich, too, which doesn't hurt.
所以你想“见鬼去吧，新奥尔良”
So you think, "The hell with New Orleans.
“现在我要说愿意还要去乡下生活”
"Now I'll say yes and go live in the country.
“我不介意给她生一群孩子”
"I wouldn't mind giving him half a dozen kids after all.
“照料房子，随便做些事情”
"Take care of a house. Do something. What the hell?"
唔，愿主使你的灵魂安息吧，布赖特·马克贝恩
Well, God rest your soul, Brett McBain.
就算他需要去使你脱离恶魔的控制
Even if he's going to have a job pulling you out of the devil's grip.
我仍旧愿意发誓他一定在什么地方留下了财产
Still, I swear he'd left money around someplace.
如果你能发现就归你好了
If you can find it, you're welcome to it.
马克贝恩夫人要回文明社会去了
Mrs. McBain goes back to civilization.
少了一个丈夫，却多了一个好前程
Minus a husband and plus a great future.
你应该过得更好
You deserve better.
上一个对我那样说的男人就埋在那儿
The last man who told me that is buried out there.
知道吗，吉儿，你让我想到了我母亲
You know, Jill, you remind me of my mother.
她是阿兰梅达最出名的妓女
She was the biggest whore in Alameda
世界上最好的女人
and the finest woman that ever lived.
无论我父亲是谁，一个小时抑或一个月
Whoever my father was, for an hour or for a month,
他都一定是个开心的男人
he must have been a happy man.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
夏恩是对的
Cheyenne's right.
一旦你杀了四个人，很容易再去杀第五个
Once you've killed four, it's easy to make it five.
现在还不是走的时候
This isn't the time to leave.
给我点水
Give me some water...
从井里
From the well.
我喜欢干净的水
I like my water fresh.
如果你听到奇怪的声响，就匐倒在地上
When you hear a strange sound, drop to the ground.
声响？什么声响？
A sound? Like what?
就像那样
Like that.
他不止会吹口琴，还能开枪
He not only plays, he can shoot, too.
早上好，马克贝恩夫人
Morning, Mrs. McBain.
- 什么风把你吹到这儿来了？ - 早上好
- What brings you to town?    - Good morning.
也许你不记得了，昨天在葬礼上…
Maybe you don't remember, but yesterday at the funeral...
我记得很清楚
I remember very well.
有什么我可以帮你的吗？
Is there something I can do for you?
是的
Yes.
去见弗兰克 告诉他我什么都知道了
See Frank. And tell him I know everything.
为什么每个人都找我打听弗兰克这家伙？
Why is everybody hounding me about this guy Frank?
我不认识他 我从未听说过他
I don't know him. I've never heard of him.
我也很苦恼，我想安安稳稳的生活
I got my own worries, and all I want is to be left in peace.
告诉弗兰克，我想和他谈判 亲自！
Tell Frank I want to negotiate with him. Personally.
告诉过你任何情况都不要来这里
You were told not to come here for any reason.
我不管你和弗兰克有什么交易，离这里远一点
Whatever business you have with Frank, keep it far away from here.
我知道，莫顿先生
Yes, I know, Mr. Morton,
但是当我听到那个女人说他知道一切时
but when I heard that woman say she knew everything,
我觉得对我来说最重要的事情就是来这儿
I thought that the important thing was for me to come over here
告诉你这些
right away and tell you about it.
你没有想到会是个圈套吗？
You never thought it wasn't a trick?
当然，但是你知道我非常谨慎，弗兰克
Sure, but you know that I'm mighty careful, Frank.
没有人能跟着我
No one could have followed me.
那是我为你工作学到的第一件事
That's the first thing I learned, working for you.
去听看不到的，去看听不到的
To listen unseen and to watch unheard.
你应该去学习如何仿佛不存在一样生活
You should learn to live as if you didn't exist.
你认识我很长时间了，弗兰克
You've known me a long time, Frank.
你知道你可以相信我
You know you can trust me.
无赖的家伙
Wobbles.
谁会相信一个穿着吊带库却系皮带的家伙？
How can you trust a man who wears both a belt and suspenders?
他连自己的裤子都不相信
The man can't even trust his own pants.
我们离开这里
Let's get out of here.
线路的终点
The end of the line.
是啊
Yeah.
带他上来
Get him on board.
捆上他
Tie him up.
等一等，弗兰克
Wait, Frank.
我没有…
I didn't...
好啊，没有人跟踪你？
So, nobody followed you?
没有，你应该相信我
No. You gotta believe me.
我只能这样相信你
So, this is the way I can trust you.
我可以解释 我不知道那家伙…
I can explain. I didn't know that he...
- 滚出去 - 不，弗兰克
- Get out. - No. No. No, Frank.
滚出去
Get out.
弗兰克，等一下！
Frank, wait!
我告诉你不要出声
I told you to keep quiet.
洛根和吉姆呢？解决掉那个女人了吗？
Where are Logan and Jim? They take care of the woman?
一些人在处理他们
Someone took care of them.
我们在马克贝恩家附近发现了他们
We found them out at McBain's place.
史通死了 那个女人不见了
Stone dead. And the woman was gone.
你朋友们的死亡率很高么 弗兰克
Your friends have a high mortality rate, Frank.
早先的三个，又有两个
First three, then two.
你就是那个约我的家伙
So you're the one who makes appointments.
你就是那个没有赴约的家伙
And you're the one who doesn't keep them.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
你是谁？
Who are you?
戴夫·詹金斯
Dave Jenkins.
戴夫·詹金斯很久以前就死了
Dave Jenkins is dead a long time ago.
卡德·本森
Calder Benson.
你的名字？本森也已经死了
What's your name? Benson's dead, too.
你应该清楚，弗兰克，比别人都清楚
You ought to know, Frank, better than anyone.
你杀了他们
You killed him.
你是谁？！
Who are you?
- 你到底是谁？你… - 弗兰克！
- Who are you, you...    - Frank!
那个女人
The woman.
我们这是在浪费时间
We're only losing time.
好吧
All right.
这次，我要亲自去会一会她
This time, I'll take care of her personally.
对啊，这对你来说在容易不过了
Yeah, it ought to be easy for you.
让他在这里暖和暖和
Keep him warm for me.
他要是找麻烦，就打他！
If he gives you any trouble, hit him.
不要打嘴 他还要讲话呢 而且要说很多
Not in the mouth. He's got to talk. And plenty.
在纳瓦霍悬崖等我
Meet me at the Navajo cliff.
还有，我要给我好好看着那个跛子
By the way, I want you to keep an eye on that cripple all the time.
- 明白吗？ - 知道了，弗兰克
- Understand?      - Sure, Frank.
- 看到什么人吗？ - 没有
- See anyone?         - No.
就是他！
There he is.
你只知道怎么开枪？
You only know how to shoot?
你也知道该怎么砍断绳索吧？
Or do you know how to cut, too?
嗨，你
Hey, you.
等一下
Wait a minute.
让我们好好看看你
Let's have a good look at you.
火车先生（儿语）
Hey. Mr. Choo-Choo.
找到你很容易
It's easy to find you.
你这个混蛋
Bastard.
我现在没有必要杀你
I don't have to kill you now.
你像蜗牛一样留下粘液
You leave a slime behind you like a snail.
两条美丽的亮闪闪的铁轨
Two beautiful shiny rails.
还有另外一个混蛋
There's another bastard.
他离我们越来越远
And he's getting further away every minute.
这就是了
There it is.
你丈夫给我买的
Exactly what your husband ordered from me.
他付了我现金
And seeing as how he paid cash on the barrelhead,
现在都是属于你的了
it all belongs to you.
橡木，厚木板，榉木，松木
Oak planks, beech, pine.
都是一流的木材
All first-grade lumber.
还有这些横梁，路基
And there's beams and foundation pylons.
十桶钉子，二十桶柏油，所有的工具
Ten kegs of nails, 20 barrels of tar, and all these tools.
也许他需要用这些来扩大农庄
Maybe he wanted to enlarge the farmhouse.
扩大农庄？
Enlarge the farmhouse?
他都可以建八个农庄了
He could have built at least eight of them.
顺便问一下，女士
By the way, ma'am,
马克贝恩还买了这个 说是很重要
McBain also ordered this. Said it was important.
但是他好像忘记告诉我他想在上面刷什么
Only it seems he forgot to tell me what he wanted printed on it.
车站
Station.
你说什么？
How's that again?
我说了，在上面刷“车站”
I said print "station."
在找这个吗？
Looking for this?
我受够了你的屠夫战术
I've had enough of your butcher tactics.
我知道那个女人在这儿
I know that woman is here.
我不希望再有无谓的残杀
I don't want any more useless killing.
我想跟你买那块地
I'm ready to make a deal for that land.
付给你应得的那份
To pay what's necessary.
我不想再浪费任何时间
I don't want to waste any more time.
你犯了个大错，莫顿
You've made a big mistake, Morton.
当你不在那列火车上的时候，你就像个缩头乌龟一样
When you're not on that train, you look like a turtle out of its shell.
真有趣
Just funny.
外表可怜的瘸子，还善于吹牛
Poor cripple talking big
所以没有人知道你真正的可怕面目
so nobody will know how scared you are.
弗兰克，我来这里是跟你做交易的
I'm here to make a deal, Frank.
我没有时间跟你争
I don't have time to compete with you.
跟我争？
Compete?
为什么你…
Why, you...
你自己站都站不稳
You can't even stand on your own feet by yourself.
这样足够证明你强壮了吗？
Ls that sufficient to make you feel stronger?
我能把你像烂苹果一样压扁
I could squash you like a wormy apple.
当然，不过你不会那样做
Sure, but you won't do it.
因为那对你没什么好处
Because it's not to your advantage.
不知道你还能用你那完好的脚走多远
Who knows how far you'd have gone with two good legs.
把他带回火车 看着他
Help him back to the train. Keep your eye on him.
莫顿 不用担心那块地
Morton. Don't worry about the land.
如果你想付钱的话，你可以付
If you feel like paying for it, you can pay.
不过这对你来说也没有什么区别
Of course, it won't make any difference to you
去跟新主人说吧
dealing with the new owner.
夏恩！夏恩！
Cheyenne! Hey, Cheyenne!
这里有个方树桩上面写着“水槽”
There's a square staked out here. It says "water tank."
这里也有一个 不过写着“邮局”
Over here, too. Only, it says "post office."
这个写着“畜栏”
And this one says "corral."
这里写着“教堂”
And this here "church."
这些都他妈的是什么东西？
What the hell is this?
你难道看不出来吗？
Can't you see?
这是一个火车站
It's a station.
所有围绕它的是一个小镇
And all around it, a town.
布赖特·马克贝恩的小镇
Brett McBain's town.
他疯了！
Was he crazy!
是呀，从某个特定的角度说
Yeah, in a very special way.
一个爱尔兰人
An Irishman.
他知道，或早或晚
He knew, sooner or later,
经过石板镇的铁路会继续往西去
that railroad coming through Flagstone would continue on west.
所以他研究了全国的情况来到了这里
So he looked over all this country out here
直到他发现了这片沙漠
until he found this hunk of desert.
没有人需要它
Nobody wanted it.
但是他却买了下来
But he bought it.
然后缩衣节食的过了很多年，他在等待
Then he tightened his belt, and for years, he waited.
他在等待什么呢？
Waited for what?
他在等待铁路修到这里
For the railroad to reach this point.
可是他是怎么知道铁路
But how in the hell could he be sure
一定会经过他的领地？
the railroad would pass through his property?
那些蒸汽机，运转离不开水
Them steam engines can't roll without water.
在石板镇往西50英里以内有水的地方只有这里
And the only water for 50 miles west of Flagstone is right here.
在这片土地下面
Under this land.
他不是个傻瓜，我们亲爱的朋友
He was no fool, our dead friend, huh?
他打算用这块沙漠换取相同重量的金子
He was going to sell this piece of desert for its weight in gold, wasn't he?
你不会卖掉你毕生的梦想
You don't sell the dream of a lifetime.
布赖特·马克贝恩只是想要他的车站
Brett McBain wanted his station.
他有权利建造它
He got the rights to build it.
- 你是怎么知道这些的？ - 我看过一份文件
- How do you know all this? - I saw a document.
一切都井井有条 图章，签字，所有一切
It was all in order. Seals, signatures, everything.
只有一件东西
One thing, though.
用很小的字写的，是个简短的条款
In very small print, there is a short clause,
说马克贝恩或者他的继承人会失去所有的权利
which says that McBain or his heirs lose all rights
如果铁路到达这个地方的时候
if, by the time the railroad reaches this point,
车站还没有建造好
the station ain't built yet.
说到铁路，我想起了路匪…
Speaking of railroads, I noticed the rail gang's already...
我注意到路匪早就藏在这些山的后面
I noticed the rail gang's already behind those hills.
在你注意到这点之前，他们就会来到这里
And before you know it, they're gonna be here.
是啊
Yeah.
听着
Listen.
口琴家
Harmonica.
一个小镇要是建造在铁路附近
A town built around the railroad.
你就可以发财了，明白吗？
You could make a fortune, huh?
成百个一千美元
Hundreds of thousands of dollars.
或者更多
Hey, more than that.
成千个一千
Thousands of thousands.
他们说那是上百万
They call them millions.
上百万？
Millions?
- 对，上百万 - 对
- Yeah, millions. - Yeah.
我一直在想，如果跟一个聪明的女士做生意会来得容易些
I always thought it'd be easier to make a deal with a smart lady.
你所要做的就是…
All you gotta do is...
你们他妈的都一个个杵在这里做什么？！
Hey, what in the hell are you standing around for?
头儿，我们应该做什么？
But, chief, what are we supposed to do?
你们应该做什么？
What are you supposed to do?
建造车站，笨蛋！
Build a station, idiots!
我想她不一定会喜欢这个车站
I figure it ain't gonna look like much.
但是这将是她回来的时候所看见的第一件东西
But it'll be the first thing she sees when she gets back.
如果她会回来的话
If she gets back.
我想…
I think...
是啊
Yeah.
我想，如果杀了你的话我会很后悔
I'm beginning to think I might be a little sorry killing you.
你喜欢活着
You like being alive.
你也喜欢男人的手抚摸你的全身
You also like to feel a man's hands all over you.
你喜欢这样
You like it.
甚至那是杀了你丈夫的那个男人的双手
Even if they're the hands of the man who killed your husband.
真是个…
What a...
真是个小骚货
What a little tramp.
在这个世界上是不是没有比保养皮肤更重要的事情了？
Is there anything in the world you wouldn't do to save your skin?
没有了，弗兰克
Nothing, Frank.
现在我明白了为什么他们那么想念你
Now I understand why they miss you so much
在那里，在新奥尔良
down there in New Orleans.
伟大的发明，电报
Great invention, the telegraph.
“吉儿？那个深色皮肤的女人？”
"Jill? The brunette?
“波旁街上妓院里的那个
"My God, all the customers
最有绅士风度的客人
"of the most elegant whorehouse on Bourbon Street
自从她离开了之后，一直伤心哭泣
"have been weeping ever since she left."
说，告诉我
Say, tell me.
老马克贝恩知道这些吗？
Did old McBain know?
当然
Yeah.
当然，我打赌他知道
Yeah, I bet he did.
只有他才是那种跟妓女结婚的人
He was just the type to marry a whore.
我有个好主意
It's an idea.
我可以跟你结婚
I could marry you.
不过那块土地要属于我
And the land would become mine.
或许
And maybe
你能成为一个完美的妻子
you'd make a perfect wife.
不过我不会是一个好丈夫
It would be me who wouldn't be any good as a husband.
太坏了
Too bad.
我们必须另外想出一个解决的办法
We'll have to think of another solution.
更简单
Simpler.
更快捷
Quicker.
作为本郡的行政长官
As sheriff of this county,
我被邀请主持这次拍卖
I've been asked to preside over the sale by auction
所有属于吉儿·马克贝恩夫人的财产，就在这儿
of all property belonging to Mrs. Jill McBain, here present.
这片土地总共320英亩
This parcel of land measures 320 acres.
土地没有任何纠纷，留置权和抵押
It's free of all encumbrances, liens and mortgages.
这块地及其所含的
This property and all it contains,
所有的资产
lock, stock and barrel,
都将在成交之时过户给幸运的买主
will be turned over to the lucky purchaser at the time of sale.
所有的东西都编号排列在
All the contents therein are listed by number
分发给你们的存货表格上
on the inventory sheet distributed among you.
全部财产将捆绑卖给出价最高的投标人
The entire property will be sold in block to the highest bidder.
好了 大家都明白了吧
All right. That's clear to everybody.
我宣布拍卖开始
I declare the auction open.
现在，谁第一个竞拍？
Now, who's going to make the first bid?
这是所有物品的清单 其中一些很值钱的
A list of all the items. Some of them are worth money.
好了，现在谁第一个竞拍？
All right. Now, who's going to make the first bid?
200美元！
$200.
好，我们有人出价200美元
Well, I have an opening bid of $200.
200美元 有没有更多的？
$200. Do I hear more?
那块臭地不值那么多钱
That stinking piece of land ain't worth it.
是不是，老前辈？
Is it, old-timer?
哦，朋友，200美元
Come on, my friends, $200.
那些牲畜就值两倍的价钱
The livestock alone is worth twice that much.
那么…
Well...
有人出300美元吗？
Who's going to bid $300?
现在，朋友们
Now, look, friends,
我知道我们不是在拍卖加州
I realize we're not offering California here,
但是200美元对于这块土地也太少了点
but 200 is damn little for all that property.
女士们，先生们，我不会接受200美元的押金
Ladies and gentlemen, I wouldn't even take 200 as a deposit.
嗯，没有人再加价了吗？
Well, nobody's going to bid it up.
你确信你不需要设一个最低竞价吗？
You're sure you wouldn't want to set a minimum price?
我希望我是错的，马克贝恩夫人
I wish I were wrong, Mrs. McBain,
但是你有义务结束这次拍卖，就算卖得很便宜
but you're liable to end up selling the place for a plate of beans.
我只想把它卖了
All I want is to sell.
- 你真胖吗？ - 如果你那么说
- You look fat, huh? - If you say so.
- 多少？ - 一张牌
- How many? - One card.
给我一张
One for me.
庄家拿三张
Dealer takes three.
我能加入吗？
Can I... Can I take a hand?
十五
Fifteen.
行啊，坐下
Yeah, sit down.
我做庄
I'll deal.
你怎么…
How do you...
你怎么玩法, 莫顿先生？
How do you play this game, Mr. Morton?
很简单
It's very simple.
只要用脑子，你就不会输
As long as you use your head, you never lose.
500美元
$500.
还有没有更高的价钱？
Do I hear any other bids?
没有了
I don't think so.
对不起，马克贝恩夫人
I'm sorry, Mrs. McBain,
但是我想我要最后敲定价钱了
but I think I'm gonna have to knock down on that last bid.
500美元一次
$500 once.
500美元两次
$500 twice.
- 500美元… - 5000美元
- $500... - $5,000.
- 是你说5000美元吗？ - 他来了
- You said $5,000? - It's on its way.
那是夏恩！
It's Cheyenne!
这个家伙值5000美元赏金，对吗？
The reward for this man is $5,000, that right?
犹大满足于4,970美元或更少
Judas was content with $4,970 less.
那个时候他们不用美元
There were no dollars in them days.
但是他狗娘养的，是啊
But sons of bitches, yeah.
等一下
Hey, wait a minute.
- 监狱在那边 - 是啊，我知道
- The jail's that way. - Yeah, I know.
是啊，但是你在去火车站
Yeah, but you're going to the railroad station.
我要送你去尤马, 夏恩
I'm sending you to Yuma, Cheyenne.
那儿有座现代化的监狱
They got a modern jail there.
那里有更多的墙，更多的栅栏，更多的侍卫
It's got more walls, more bars, more guards.
你会喜欢的，在那里20年，你会知道的
You'll like it, in 20 years. You'll see.
两张票，朋友，去下一站
Two tickets, amigo, to the next station.
单程
One way only.
这是给你的 祝贺你
Here's to you. And congratulations.
你做了个好买卖
You got yourself a good deal.
拍卖
The auction.
忘了它吧 我没有投资那块地
Forget it. I don't invest in land.
你一点儿也不像个高尚的保护可怜无助的寡妇的人
You don't look at all like the noble defender of poor defenseless widows.
不过，也是
But then again,
我也不像一个可怜无助的寡妇
I don't look like a poor defenseless widow.
夏恩是对的 你是一个不平常的女人
Cheyenne's right. You're a remarkable woman.
你是一个不平常的男人
And you're a remarkable man.
但是你现在已经想到什么了
But you have something on your mind.
你想到什么了？
And you got something on your mind.
热水 满满一澡盆热水
Hot water. A bathtub full of hot water.
我想是时候了 我去放水
I think it's time I filled that bathtub.
你是谁？
Who are you?
吉姆·库珀
Jim Cooper.
查克·扬不拉德
Chuck Youngblood.
多一个死人
More dead men.
要不是遇见了你，他们都还活着，弗兰克
They were all alive until they met you, Frank.
你为那属于我的东西付了5000美元
You paid $5,000 for something that belongs to me.
5000美元
5,000.
加上一块钱
Plus one.
你也有权利得到一点利润
You've got a right to make a profit, too.
我不会想太久，如果我是你的话
I wouldn't take too long thinking about it, if I were you.
你把自己卷入了自己能力之外的事情
You got yourself into something that's bigger than you are.
你现在有机会全身而退，最好收下
You got a chance to get out easy. You better take it.
你像一个真正的生意人，弗兰克
You sound like a real businessman, Frank.
跟莫顿先生在一起对你很有帮助
Being with Mr. Morton has done you a lot of good.
而且你还学到一些新方法
And you've learned some new methods.
是的，莫顿先生教了我很多新的方法
Yeah, Mr. Morton has shown you a lot of new ways.
虽然你还没有放弃你的老方法
Even though you haven't given up the old ones.
任选一种你喜欢的方法 做完这宗买卖
Pick any method you like. Just make the deal.
哪一宗买卖，弗兰克？
Which deal, Frank?
我们不止一宗，你我之间
We have more than one, you and me.
我们可以把它们捆在一起，一起解决
We can lump them together into one bundle, settle all of them.
就这儿，现在
Here and now.
放松，弗兰克
Easy, Frank.
放松
Easy.
你要学习如何解决问题
You gotta learn not to push things.
放轻松是一个生意人必须作的第一件事
Taking it easy is the first thing a businessman should do.
我有个主意 莫顿先生能教你更多的东西
I got an idea Mr. Morton can teach you a lot more.
多少钱？
How much?
一块钱
$1.
驾！
Giddy up!
我发誓我们会听到那种奇怪的声音
I could swear we're going to have that strange sound.
现在
Right now.
时间过得真快
Time sure flies.
已经过了12点了
It's already past 12:00.
但是他们是他的人
But... But they were his men.
- 是啊 - 他们想要杀了他
- Yeah. - And they tried to kill him.
有人出更高的价
They must have found somebody who pays better.
你！
And you!
你却救了他
You saved his life.
我只是不让他们杀他，那不是一回事
I didn't let them kill him and that's not the same thing.
对
Sure.
那不是一回事
It's not the same thing.
你快穿好衣服
You get dressed.
是时候回家了
It's time to go home.
煮咖啡了吗？
Did you make coffee?
这次我煮了
This time I did.
味道很好
Good.
我母亲就是这样煮咖啡的
My mother used to make coffee this way.
热热的，浓浓的而且味道很好
Hot, strong and good.
夏恩
Cheyenne.
他在那里等什么？
What's he waiting for out there?
他在做什么？
What's he doing?
他在削一块木头
He's whittling on a piece of wood.
我有预感当他削完的时候
I got a feeling when he stops whittling,
会有什么事情发生
something's gonna happen.
见到我很吃惊吗？
Surprised to see me here?
我知道你会来的
I knew you'd come.
莫顿曾经跟我说过我永远都不会跟他一样
Morton once told me I could never be like him.
现在我知道为什么了
Now I understand why.
如果没有去找他，你就会知道你还是属于某个地方
Wouldn't have bothered him, knowing you were around somewhere alive.
所以你发现你根本就不是一个生意人？
So you found out you're not a businessman after all?
只是一个人而已
Just a man.
一个古老的人种
An ancient race.
其他的莫顿们会过来 他们会把它消灭
Other Mortons will be along and they'll kill it off.
未来跟我们无关
The future don't matter to us.
现在也无关
Nothing matters now.
不为土地，不为钱，也不为女人
Not the land, not the money, not the woman.
我来这里是要找你
I came here to see you.
因为我知道你现在会告诉我你在寻找什么
'Cause I know that now you'll tell me what you're after.
只有在死亡的那一刻
Only at the point of dying.
我知道
I know.
我为你热了一些水，我还找到一个剃刀
I heated some water for you. I also found a razor.
放在那儿好了
Put it there, please.
我可以在剃胡子的时候看到火车开过来
So I can watch the railroad move up while I shave.
你知道吗？
You know what?
如果我是你，我就会下去给那些人一些水喝
If I was you, I'd go down there and give those boys a drink.
你不能想象
You can't imagine
能看到你这样的女人会让男人有多么高兴
how happy it makes a man to see a woman like you.
只是看着她
Just to look at her.
如果其中有人在后面拍你
And if one of them should pat your behind,
就装作什么都没有
just make believe it's nothing.
他们值得那个
They earned it.
让你亲爱的兄弟高兴
Keep your loving brother happy.
你是谁？
Who... Who are you?
你是个英俊的男人
Hey. You're sort of a handsome man.
但是我不是那个人
But I'm not the right man.
他也不是
And neither is he.
或许不是
Maybe not.
但是那不重要了
But it doesn't matter.
你不明白，吉儿
You don't understand, Jill.
那样的人总是有些东西藏在心里
People like that have something inside.
一些跟死亡有关的东西
Something to do with death.
如果那个家伙还活着，他会从那扇门进来
If that fella lives, he'll come in through that door,
拿起他的行李说再见
pick up his gear and say adiós.
能看到这个小镇建成真得很好
It would be nice to see this town grow.
现在我要走了
Now I gotta go.
这里将成为一个美丽的小镇 甜水
Gonna be a beautiful town, Sweetwater.
我希望你将来能回来
I hope you'll come back someday.
将来
Someday.
是啊… 我也要走了
Yeah. I gotta go, too.
让人们相信什么都没有发生过
Make believe it's nothing.
对不起，口琴家
Sorry, Harmonica.
我要留在这里了
I gotta stay here.
谁干的？
Who?
我遇到了火车先生
I ran into Mr. Choo-Choo.
我没有考虑到火车上那个废人
I didn't count on that half-man from the train.
他看起来很害怕
He got scared.
口琴家
Hey, Harmonica.
当他们射中你的时候
When they do you in,
真希望那家伙知道该往哪儿打
pray it's somebody who knows where to shoot.
走开
Go away.
走开，我不希望你看着我死
Go away. I don't want you to see me die.